ANJALI RAMANI

PROFILE

I am a Senior at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, majoring in Animal Science and minoring in Business & Computer Science. I absolutely love animals and believe they deserve the best quality of life. I have comprehensive companion animal care experience and am extremely knowledgeable in a wide variety of behavior patterns.

CONTACT



12510 JOLENE CT, SARATOGA, CA 669 226 9995



DRAMANI2@ILLINOIS.EDU

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018:

ANIMAL SCIENCE B.S.

Minor | Computer Science & Business
UNIVERISITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN

2010 - 2014:

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

AMERICAN INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL CHENNAI

ORGANIZATIONS & SPORTS

LUYANDO BOXING

CHAMPAIGN, IL

ILLINI BOXING CLUB

UNIVERISITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN TREASURER & ASSISTANT COACH

PRE-VETERNARY CLUB

UNIVERISITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN

COMPANION ANIMALS CLUB

UNIVERISITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN

TEACHERS 4 CREATURES

UNIVERISITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA-CHAMPAIGN

ACHIEVEMENTS

119LB NATIONAL BOXING CHAMPION

VIRGINIA MILITARY INSTITUTE | 2017

EXPERIENCE

2016 - PRESENT | UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA CHAMPAIGN UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Laboratory of Integrative Immunology and Behavior

- Provided care for neonatal piglets & Sows infected with PRRSV
- Assisted in Sow C-Sections
- Microglial Isolation & MRI Scans & Brain Tracings

SPRING OF 2016 | UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA CHAMPAIGN LAB WORKING WITH FARM ANIMALS

Extensive hands-on interaction with domestic farm animals with a weekly lab rotations:

- DAIRY FARM: Haltering, milking & checking for mastitis.
- POULTRY FARM: Weighing chicks/ chickens, vaccinations & checking blood for salmonella. And performed necropsy on chicks and older sick chickens.
- BEEF FARM: Handling of cows & performing nitrogen freeze branding.

FALL OF 2016 | UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA CHAMPAIGN LAB HORSE MANAGAMENT

Taking care of Foals - getting them used to halters and walking on a lead and the trailers!

SUMMER OF 2015 | REDWOOD CITY, CA

GUEST SERVICE TEAM MEMBER

Looked over the care of 200 dogs and 20 cats at a time:

- Preparing and passing out meals
- Administering medications as directed by the owner
- Managing dog play groups about 50 dogs.
- Disinfecting the companion animal's rooms & Changed animal's bedding on a regular basis.

2012 - 2014 | CHENNAI, INDIA

KENNEL ASSISTANT | BLUE CROSS ANIMAL SANTUARY

Provided care for companion animals, small animals, birds and livestock animals.

- Provided food, water and medications daily.
- Disinfected animal cages/kennels.
- Inspected animals for signs of injury or infection as needed and reported back to the veterinarian.
- Groomed and bathed companion animals on a rotating basis.

2010 - PRESENT | CHENNAI, INDIA & SARATOGA, CA

FOSTER PARENT

Rescued stray/orphaned companion animals from dire situations (Car accidents, heavy storms, abuse, etc.) and provided care until rehomed.

- Provided companion animals with food, water and medications daily.
- Bottle-fed orphaned puppies and kittens.
- Groomed and bathed companion animals on a rotating basis.
- Changed bandages and cleaned wounds or incisions from surgery (
- Rescued over 50 dogs and 30 cats.